<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 14:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Valentine’s day is just around the corner. Lovers and relationship hopefuls will spend an estimated $18.9 billion (according to NRF) on gifts, dinners and more on the big day. With customers in love and ready to spend, here are 5 steps you can count to help you reach successful Valentine’s day sales. 1. Think Mobile [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/">5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Valentine’s day is just around the corner. Lovers and relationship hopefuls will spend an estimated <a href="https://nrf.com/media/press-releases/cupid-shower-americans-jewelry-candy-this-valentines-day" target="_blank">$18.9 billion (according to NRF)</a> on gifts, dinners and more on the big day. With customers in love and ready to spend, here are 5 steps you can count to help you reach successful Valentine’s day sales.<br />
<span id="more-21140"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">1. Think Mobile</h2>
<p>Mobile is fast becoming the preferred shopping channel in leading ecommerce markets like the UK and Germany. With <a href="http://resources.mobify.com/50-mobile-commerce-stats.html" target="_blank">30% of customers saying they’ll abandon a mobile</a> purchase if the site isn’t optimized, you would do well to make this a priority during peak sales periods like Valentine’s Day. Make sure your emails are adapted to mobile viewing, and that the transition from email to site to checkout is seamless. If your website isn’t mobile-responsive already, make that first on your list of things to do to get ready for the sales season.</p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">2. Create an attractive offer</h2>
<p>As with other sale periods, the challenge at Valentine’s Day is to come up with an offer that stands out from the crowd. Merchants who sell traditional Valentine’s Day goods like flowers, chocolates, stuffed animals and lingerie will be under exceptional pressure to catch the consumer eye. Discounts are an obvious option, but playing on price alone can be hit or miss. Consider offering <a href="https://www.ice-watch.com/uk-en/ice-sili/ice-love-p-26729.htm?coul_att_detailID=1266&amp;utm_source=B2C+-+Customers+-+Contacts+-+Ice-Watch&amp;utm_campaign=97b098e6ae-2016_01_14_love_teaser_ALL_ALL&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_b847164ea2-97b098e6ae-273191485&amp;mc_cid=97b098e6ae&amp;mc_eid=754b62a6a1" target="_blank">limited edition items</a> or custom product bundles that play on a sense of urgency and the current holiday theme. </p>
<p>Another option is to combine attractive sales with personalized marketing efforts. Valentine’s Day is stressful for some people, so offering an added value in the form of gift guides, curation, or even a vamped up live chat can be the detail that convinces customers to shop with you. Think about what problem or desire your products respond to, and then focus on getting that message to your customers via your blog, newsletter and email campaigns. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">3. Promote</h2>
<p>After you’ve come up with the perfect offer, make sure customers are aware of your sale. Here are a few suggestions:</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/"><strong>Pop Ups or Pop Ins</strong></a><br />
Pop-ups and pop-ins promote your sale to people who are already on your website. Because they take up your entire web page, they’re sure to capture shoppers’ attention&#8211; but they can also be seen as disruptive. Be sure to place limitations on the number of times a shopper will receive the prompt so they don’t leave with a bad impression.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-awesome-ideas-valentines-day-gift-guides/"><strong>Gift Guides</strong></a><br />
Gift guides are a versatile way to promote your products. They’re especially helpful for shoppers who are stymied for gift ideas, or who waited until the last minute. A well put-together gift guide directs shoppers with different needs to the perfect present. If you have a blog, use it to showcase your products to your readers. Consider putting together an advice-based post that gives customers added value in addition to presenting your product.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/"><strong>Email Marketing</strong></a><br />
Email remains one of the most effective ways of getting your message out: you reach directly into your customer’s inbox for a chance to grab their attention and drive traffic to your website. Be sure you have a catchy subject line to reel them in, and that the transition from inbox to landing page goes off without a hitch. Depending on your promotion, you might also consider a multi-tiered email campaign that divides the focus between price-based offers and <a href="http://www.splio4.com/mr/6fU0is7q4/3390/1877180697.html" target="_blank">unique value adds</a> that are likely to differentiate you from the competition. Think about how you can delight your customer this year, in addition to saving her money.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-launching-sem-campaign-google-adwords/"><strong>Google Ads</strong></a><br />
This is potentially the most costly promotion tool in your marketing kit. Whether you manage your campaign directly with Google Adwords, or use a third-party service provider, you’ll have to pay to use this option. Around holiday sales, bids for keywords like “Valentine’s Day” and “Gifts” tend to be higher. However, the visibility you will gain has great earning potential for your website. You should evaluate your resources and allocate budget accordingly; Google Ads can be a great boost, but if you don’t have a compelling offer or give customers a reason to trust you, then no amount of traffic will help you reach your sales goals.</p>
<p>- <strong>Website banner displays</strong><br />
Just like popups and popins, website banners only promote your sale to people already shopping on your site. The advantage is that a banner is not as intrusive, and unlike popups and popins, customers can’t simply close and forget about them. (Here&#8217;s how to change them with the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/">default template</a>). They’re a great place to use theme-specific images and highlight perks like free shipping and gift wrapping. Think about adding in a shipping cut off reminder as well. Everything you do to simplify the shopping experience gets you a step closer to a conversion.</p>
<p>- <strong>Social Media</strong><br />
Promoting your sale on social media is a great way to reach shoppers who are interested but haven’t made a purchase with you. It’s also a great opportunity for your ad to be shared among shoppers’ online friends. You might consider a social-only promotion or contest to drum up interest.</p>
<p>Do you know you plan on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/">promoting your valentine&#8217;s day sales</a>? For more help and advice, check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/">Valentine&#8217;s Day Marketing</a> article! </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">4. Test</h2>
<p>With a limited time to convert customers, it’s important to test your website and the offers that you’ve developed. Make sure the coupons and promotions you’re promoting actually work: it sounds obvious, but when you’re rushing to get things just right and in time, there’s always a possibility of a technical error slipping in. Don’t wait to find out on the day of the sale.</p>
<p>Besides testing your promotions, here are a few other tasks you should complete before you launch your sale: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Test links from all your advertising</li>
<li>Try placing an order (this is especially critical when you allow customers to customize products)</li>
<li>Complete the order with each of your payment options. There is nothing worse than having a customer discard a purchase because they were unable to pay.</li>
</ul>
<p>Valentine’s Day is a big one for last-minute orders, so it’s more important than ever to ensure quick and easy ordering. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">5. Analyze</h2>
<p>Last, but certainly not least: schedule time for post-holiday sales analysis. Use this time to review your sales predictions and to see if the sales met or fell short of your target goals. Ask yourself questions like: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What worked well this year?</li>
<li>What can be improved?</li>
<li>Which trends would we like to test for the next holiday sale?</li>
<li>Which trends were surprising and warrant another look?</li>
<li>Which ideas, if any, should we stop testing?</li>
</ul>
<p>The conclusions you draw from your analysis will be important for making predictions for your next sales holiday. It&#8217;s also important to analyze the products you have leftover and brainstorm another promotion to clear this year&#8217;s Valentine&#8217;s Day products. </p>
<hr width="20%" align="left" />
<p>Are you ready for Valentine&#8217;s day 2016? Share any tips you’ve learned in the comments or come back and tell us how these steps helped you achieve your sales goal this year! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/">5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Success Story: How crazy is it to sell perishable goods online? Not Half Nuts!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 13:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21123</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The seamless process of online shopping&#8211;click a button and receive your goods&#8211;means many of us take for granted the complicated logistics that allow our online purchases to make it to our doorstep without delay. In today’s success story, Mary Ziegler, co-owner of HalfNuts.net, let’s us in on how her company makes sure every package arrives [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/">Success Story: How crazy is it to sell perishable goods online? Not Half Nuts!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The seamless process of online shopping&#8211;click a button and receive your goods&#8211;means many of us take for granted the complicated logistics that allow our online purchases to make it to our doorstep without delay. In today’s success story, Mary Ziegler, co-owner of <a href="https://www.halfnuts.net/" target="_blank">HalfNuts.net</a>, let’s us in on how her company makes sure every package arrives with a hitch.<br />
<span id="more-21123"></span><br />
<strong>JL: Tell us about Half Nuts and the products you sell.</strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> As our name suggests, we sell a wide variety of nuts that are raw, roasted, salted, and even topped with delectable coatings, such as chocolate or butter toffee. The other half of Half Nuts is a wide assortment of candies, chocolates, dried fruit, snack mixes and most notably, our proprietary Ziegler Giant Bar.  </p>
<p><strong>JL: What is the Ziegler Giant Bar? </strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> The Ziegler Giant Bar was candy bar created by The Ziegler Candy Company. The name is no coincidence&#8230; the Ziegler Candy Company was run by my husband’s family for four generations before they closed in the 1970s. Growing up around the candy factory inspired my husband to make candy a part of his career path at Half Nuts. Today, we continue to offer the original Giant Bar in the same molds, with the same recipe, as an homage to the Ziegler Candy family history. </p>
<p><strong>JL: How did your online store come to be? </strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> We started in our brick and mortar business in 1990. As a convenience to our local customers, we set up a website and listed all of our products online, so they could see what we had and shop without actually coming to the store. Since our first website debuted in 2002, we’ve redesigned and re-launched it several times before settling on the current one. We have expanded from just our online catalog for our local community, to becoming a full scale national retailer of nuts, candy, and lots of other treats.</p>
<p>When we hired our web developer, Arafat, we were impressed with his website portfolio and the overall design of the shop. That’s why we’ve stayed with him since PrestaShop 1.5.6 and have recently upgraded to PrestaShop 1.6. Arafat takes much pride in his work, and has custom built us a great PrestaShop website.</p>
<p><strong>JL: What challenges have you encountered selling perishable goods?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> The main challenge we have shipping the products is the fact that they are perishable and we want them to arrive as fresh as possible. The perks of living in Milwaukee include having nice cool shipping weather for most of the year. However, as our sales grew online and we started shipping much more to the South, but also to the East and the West coasts, we had to deal with the hot weather those regions are apt to have.  Some have shipping weather all year round that is poses a problem for us. Our vendors often use ice bricks to ship product to us, and we then offer those ice bricks to our customers for free.  </p>
<p>Although this helped keep the products cool, the weight of the ice bricks increased the shipping costs for our customer. Because of this, we implemented the Connect to <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/518-shipping-logistics" target="_blank">UPS</a> and the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-costs/20047-usps-rate-calculator-pro.html" target="_blank">USPS Shipping</a> modules, to let our customers pick the shipping option they prefer. We let them choose whether they want a service that tells them the exact date they’ll receive their package, like UPS does, or if they prefer the less expensive option, with the United States Postal Service.</p>
<p>Another thing that we offer are Styrofoam coolers. These provide great insulation for the “meltables” we ship, without excessively weighing them down.  While it cuts down on weight, it still increases costs due to the size of the package.  This is why we use two shipping modules that offer two different shipping options.  Letting our customers choose their own shipping method has helped keep our costs down and in turn, keeps our customers happy. </p>
<p><strong>JL: With holidays like Valentine’s around the corner, how do you prepare? </strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> Valentine’s, Easter, Halloween, and Christmas&#8230;all the major holidays&#8230;are busy times for us. We start promoting for these events about 15 days ahead of time for the smaller holidays, and a month prior to the major ones like Christmas and Easter. We’ll add features like <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pop-in-pop-up/19431-pop-promo.html" target="_blank">a pop-up notification</a> and we offer holiday discounts for online orders. For current customers, we’ll remind them about our store with an <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/500-newsletter-sms" target="_blank">email marketing</a> campaign and offer the same holiday discount. To prepare logistically, for holidays and other busy times, we always arrange extra staff to fulfill orders on a timely basis, usually within 24 hours.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Do you think you have what it takes to start selling perishable goods online? Get started today with our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/">eCommerce software</a>. Want more inspiration? Check out other PrestaShop merchants in these previous <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/category/ecommerce-success-stories/">success stories</a>!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/">Success Story: How crazy is it to sell perishable goods online? Not Half Nuts!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should your online store offer gift cards?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 13:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that in 2014 gift card spending grew to $100 billion? Since their inception, gift cards have steadily grown in popularity. Today we’ll go over the basics of gift cards to help you determine if they’re a good fit for your online shop. What are gift cards? There are 2 major kinds of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/">Should your online store offer gift cards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that in <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/news/2015/inside-the-motives-of-a-gift-card-buyer-why-the-industry-continues-to-boom/" target="_blank">2014 gift card spending grew to $100 billion</a>? Since their inception, gift cards have steadily grown in popularity. Today we’ll go over the basics of gift cards to help you determine if they’re a good fit for your online shop.<br />
<span id="more-21121"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">What are gift cards?</h2>
<p>There are 2 major kinds of gift cards: open-loop (bank) gift cards, which are supported by major payment solutions like Visa, MasterCard and American Express, and closed-loop  (or retail) cards,  which are only accepted at specific retailers. In this article, we’ll just be addressing closed-loop gift cards your own shop can issue. </p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">Gift card pros for online stores</h2>
<p>Gift cards are great not only for customers, but also for the merchants who sell them. Here are a few great reasons to offer gift cards on your online shop: </p>
<ol>
<li>It’s easy for the customer&#8211;they don’t need to know the recipient’s address or preferences.</li>
<li>End customers get to pick products they actually want, which reduces the number of returns on your site.</li>
<li>Your cash flow gets a boost: you’ll be paid before you even ship the product.</li>
<li>They’re convenient, but more personal than money.</li>
<li>Gift cards give new customers that may have been hesitant to purchase from you otherwise a reason to get to know you.</li>
<li>Customers generally pay full price and <a href="https://www.cebglobal.com/exbd/financial-services/tower-group/gift-cards/index.page?" target="_blank">spend more than the value of the gift card</a>.</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">Gift card cons for online stores</h2>
<p>Of course, with the good comes the bad. Here are some of the negatives of making gift cards available on your shop:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Increased bookkeeping.</strong> You’ll need to keep track of the initial gift card purchase, as well as the product order, which is when the gift card is actually redeemed.</li>
<li><strong>No returns, only exchanges.</strong> For most credit card processors, funds can only be returned to the original purchaser’s card. This makes issuing returns to the gift recipient impossible.</li>
<li><strong>Potential for fraud.</strong> In some instances, a scammer could purchase the gift card, then drain the value of the gift card <em>before you</em>, the merchant, realize that the original order is fraudulent.</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">How to set up gift cards in PrestaShop</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Install a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pricing-promotion-prestashop-modules/17452-gift-card.html" target="_blank">gift card module</a>.</strong> Although it’s possible to manually create each gift card as customers purchase them with our built-in voucher capabilities, we’ve created a module that helps you manage your gift cards. Once you’ve installed a gift card module, you’re ready to set it up. </li>
<li><strong>Decide on gift card amounts / denominations.</strong> You’ll want to offer gift cards in denominations that make sense for your product selection. If your average order value is , make sure you offer gift card amounts that reflect that. Offering  gift cards won’t really make sense in this example. </li>
<li><strong>Set the expiration date.</strong> Be aware of laws that regulate this in your country. For example, if you’re based <a href="http://www.ncsl.org/research/financial-services-and-commerce/gift-cards-and-certificates-statutes-and-legis.aspx" target="_blank">in the US, gift cards cannot expire within 5 years</a> of the purchase. This is just the baseline. Additional state laws may further limit the expiration date. </li>
<li><strong>Provide all product FAQ’s in the product description.</strong> For example, let customers know where the gift card is valid. If you have a physical location, can it be used there? Can the gift card be used on clearance items? If you will assess any additional fees, list them here as well. This ensures that you not only address your customer’s concerns, but you also ensure that there is no confusion about how gift cards are to be used on your website. </li>
<li><strong>List and promote your gift card.</strong> It’s not enough to just create your gift card. Be sure to add a link in your footer and try searching “gift card” in your search bar to verify that it’s easy to find. Next, try promoting the gift card on a homepage slider or in your gift product category. </li>
</ol>
<p>It’s your turn. Tell us why you do or don’t offer gift cards to your online shop. Have any good or bad experiences share them in the comments below. Not running an online shop yet? Get started today with PrestaShop. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/">Should your online store offer gift cards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2 Quick Ways Retailers Can Improve Inventory in 2016</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21134</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The holidays are over. Let’s all take a deep breath. It was the best holiday season on record for online retailers, as online sales jumped a whopping 20% over 2014; but don’t pop your leftover champagne just yet. There are a few areas of improvement that became clear during the holidays, and inventory is one [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/">2 Quick Ways Retailers Can Improve Inventory in 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The holidays are over. Let’s all take a deep breath. </p>
<p>It was the best holiday season on record for online retailers, as online sales jumped a whopping <a href="http://www.mastercardadvisors.com/modules/news/a_happy_holiday_season_for_retailers.html" target="_blank">20%</a> over 2014; but don’t pop your leftover champagne just yet. There are a few areas of improvement that became clear during the holidays, and inventory is one of them. </p>
<p>Out of stock situations are embarrassing: you work hard to get shoppers to your store with clever advertising, entice them with your great prices and helpful product descriptions&#8211;but then they can’t add an item to their cart because you’re all out of it. Let’s make sure that never happens again.<br />
<span id="more-21134"></span><br />
Inventory is an inherently messy part of retail. Even the most successful retailers have ended up with too much or too little stock at some point, but that doesn’t have to be the case anymore, thanks to data. A quick look into historical sales data and best selling products for your specific vertical can determine which products <a href="http://www.wiser.com/wisepricer?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">improve profit margins</a> and sell well consistently. Let’s dig deeper into these two ideas.</p>
<h2 style="color:#38315d">How Historical Sales Data Can Help</h2>
<p>When you change anything about your business, it’s important to have the data to figure out where you’ve come from and what impact your tweaks are making. If a product isn’t selling well, maybe it’s because the pricing was uncompetitive or maybe it’s just because unseasonably warm weather kept shoppers from buying it (this is a common issue for clothing retailers). Either way, knowing how many sold and under what conditions historically will tell you what strategy is most effective. </p>
<p>Like most parts of online retail, inventory is an ongoing process. You can’t just order once and sit back and relax. Instead, an <a href="http://www.wiser.com/assortment?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">optimized inventory</a> must be constantly reevaluated to figure out which products and in what quantities worked, and what you should avoid in the future. In the case of inventory, it’s definitely true that you have to look back in order to move forward on the best foot. </p>
<h2 style="color:#38315d">Why You Should Track Best Sellers</h2>
<p>You already know that your product assortment has a huge impact on your success as a seller and some products are more important than others. The <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/davelavinsky/2014/01/20/pareto-principle-how-to-use-it-to-dramatically-grow-your-business/" target="_blank">Pareto Principle</a> suggests that 80% of your sales will come from 20% of your stock, and that’s where best sellers come in. Having the top items in your vertical will draw shoppers to your site and your pricing will help them complete the purchase. So how do you make sure that you’re always stocked up on the hottest items that will take your online shop to the next level? </p>
<p>That’s where data comes back in. In order to find the best new products to add to your assortment, you need to keep track of how they’re selling and how they’re ranked on top marketplaces, especially Amazon. First, retailers need to choose the category or categories that will expand their selling capacity. This makes it possible to pinpoint the products that will increase sales. Next, a combination of <a href="http://blog.wiser.com/drive-the-bandwagon-how-to-catch-assortment-trends-early/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">popularity trends</a> (such as rating and rank on Amazon over time), cost, and pricing information will give you an idea of how volatile the item is and how much you’d be able to make from each sale. After all, you’ll only want to add the products that are consistently highly rated and the most profitable to make the most of your selling experience. </p>
<p>An advanced last step would be to perform a <a href="http://blog.wiser.com/how-to-enhance-assortment-discovery-using-market-price-intelligence/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">gap analysis</a> based on the top products you find. Sure, some best selling products might have slim margins, but maybe all of your competitors carry them. In that case, it might be a good idea to put your typical margins to the side and carry it anyway to avoid losing customers. You can always make up those margin dollars on unique products that you don’t have to price quite as competitively. </p>
<h2 style="color:#38315d">How to Speed up Inventory Improvement</h2>
<p>The easiest way to keep up with best sellers is by automating the process. That way you’ll never sleep on the top selling products again. Now that the holidays are over, all retailers are looking for the next top products that will speed up sales closer to where they were in mid December. The post holiday sales slump doesn’t have to be a reality with data-driven assortment planning. The combination of internal historical sales data and data from monitoring best sellers can help any retailer keep with trends and even lead the pack in their vertical.</p>
<h4 style="color:#38315d">About the Author</h4>
<p>Angelica Valentine is the Content Marketing Manager at <a href="http://www.wiser.com/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">Wiser</a>, the leading provider of data-driven pricing and merchandising solutions for retailers, brands, and manufacturers. Angelica is an Oakland native who loves writing, exploring, and participating in music, food, and cultural events around the Bay Area.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/">2 Quick Ways Retailers Can Improve Inventory in 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with Eugen Kuschnir, PrestaShop Ambassador in Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/interview-eugen-kuschnir-prestashop-ambassador-germany/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/interview-eugen-kuschnir-prestashop-ambassador-germany/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 13:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sabrina Maréchal]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Ambassadors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21113</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A little over two weeks ago, the PrestaShop community got together in Düsseldorf for its second MeetUp organized entirely by PrestaShop ambassador Eugen Kuschnir. I had the opportunity to interview Eugen about his role as ambassador and organizing local MeetUps. Eugen, first I would like to ask: how did you find out about PrestaShop? What [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/interview-eugen-kuschnir-prestashop-ambassador-germany/">Interview with Eugen Kuschnir, PrestaShop Ambassador in Germany</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A little over two weeks ago, the PrestaShop community got together in Düsseldorf for its second MeetUp organized entirely by PrestaShop ambassador Eugen Kuschnir. I had the opportunity to interview Eugen about his role as ambassador and organizing local MeetUps.<br />
<span id="more-21113"></span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/image9-1024x768.jpg" alt="image9" width="700" height="525" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21115" /></p>
<p><strong>Eugen, first I would like to ask: how did you find out about PrestaShop? What was your first experience of the shop system?</strong></p>
<p>As a software developer, I also participate in a few e-commerce projects. Almost one year ago, in December 2014, I came across PrestaShop by chance, and I was immediately sucked in. The system’s ease of use gave me a good first impression, and that was reason enough to carry out more complete tests. So I tested several scenarios, which all turned out very well at the end. Of course, the relationship with the community is also a plus. When there’s a problem, there are always developers who are there to help us. For example, I encountered some problems with a payment connection, but developers at Gurkcity found a solution.</p>
<p><strong>You decided to become a PrestaShop Ambassador. What inspired you to do this?</strong></p>
<p>On June 11, I went to the PrestaShop Day in Paris where <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">the ambassador program</a> was presented for the first time. I feel that one of the system’s main advantages lies in its open-source spirit, and I can always rely on the strong links that bring the community together. The ambassador program was the perfect opportunity to further develop my relationships with other merchants and PrestaShop agencies, and share my knowledge and experience. In short, I applied and had an interview with Hagen Meischner, the Country Manager for DACH and Sabrina Marechal, the ambassador program manager. In September I became an active ambassador – I would like to specify that it’s an unpaid, volunteer position.</p>
<p><strong>The second Community MeetUp was held on December 2. What is a MeetUp like and where is it held?</strong></p>
<p>My goal in the future is to organize a gathering for the community every month: a traditional MeetUp will be held every two months and a planning meeting will be organized in the off months. </p>
<p><strong>And you actively participate in this meeting?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, I also participate in it. Up until now, MeetUps revolved around general discussions, with topics specific to e-commerce and PrestaShop. In the future, we want to take the event further with members of the community who are interested in the technical side of things. Concrete problems will be presented for which we will discuss ideas and solutions or develop small modules. Think of it as a “mini-hackathon”. We will also talk about the technical aspects of a shop’s everyday operations. </p>
<p><strong>What do MeetUps have in store for participants?</strong></p>
<p>The fundamental idea behind the MeetUps is to bring members of a virtual community together in the real world. For that, the format of the MeetUp has proven itself effective. Whoever is interested in PrestaShop, e-commerce or any other topic is welcome: the MeetUp is free and open to all. As ambassador, I set the date, find the venue, etc. Everything is organized on Meetup.com and Eventbrite. Of course, PrestaShop helps with their blog, newsletter, social media accounts, etc. </p>
<p>The first MeetUps showed that direct discussions helped created entirely new relationships among merchants, developers, and agencies, which didn&#8217;t happen on the PrestaShop forum or on other channels. </p>
<p>Each MeetUp’s topics are chosen by the participants themselves, either directly during the MeetUp or when participants come up with an important point that will be discussed in the next MeetUp and for which preparation is needed. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/image11-1024x768.jpg" alt="image11" width="700" height="525" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21116" /></p>
<p><strong>What were the topics of the last MeetUp?</strong></p>
<p>The main theme of the last meeting was the new version of PrestaShop. In a video podcast, Sébastien Levaillant, Product Management Director, gave an overview of the next version and presented certain features. Merchants and developers expressed needs and wants that are very different for version 1.7: discussions are far from over on the subject.</p>
<p>Furthermore, there were many discussions on the test method for Trusted Shops and Händlerbund shops, as well as what merchants need to check for these tests. The Patworx agency also presented its new Amazon Payments Module at this MeetUp. With Amazon Payments, a new payment method is available to merchants that offers customers a user-friendly purchasing experience.</p>
<p>Of course, other practical issues for merchants were discussed by support, such as tips on optimizing search engines and importing CSV data. </p>
<p><strong>One last question, Eugen: what would you like to see at the next MeetUps?</strong></p>
<p>Personally, I would like for there to be more participants. For each of the two meetings, there were 15 people on-site. It was a good mix of merchants and developers, and we would love for web designers to be able to attend the next meeting. Then the MeetUps would bring together all the roles that participate in creating an online shop. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/interview-eugen-kuschnir-prestashop-ambassador-germany/">Interview with Eugen Kuschnir, PrestaShop Ambassador in Germany</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/interview-eugen-kuschnir-prestashop-ambassador-germany/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clear holiday inventory and increase sales with mystery boxes</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/clear-holiday-inventory-increase-sales-mystery-boxes/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/clear-holiday-inventory-increase-sales-mystery-boxes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 13:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21084</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With the holiday sale season coming to a close, retailers are all looking for ways to clear out their holiday inventory. Today we’re going to show you a new technique that borrows from a popular Japanese tradition called Fukubukuro, roughly translated to mystery, or even lucky, bags. We’ll tell you how you can use mystery [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/clear-holiday-inventory-increase-sales-mystery-boxes/">Clear holiday inventory and increase sales with mystery boxes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the holiday sale season coming to a close, retailers are all looking for ways to clear out their holiday inventory. Today we’re going to show you a new technique that borrows from a popular Japanese tradition called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fukubukuro" target="_blank">Fukubukuro</a>, roughly translated to mystery, or even lucky, bags. We’ll tell you how you can use mystery boxes to increase sales, help you recover from your post-holiday slump, clear out holiday inventory, and increase profits. </p>
<p><span id="more-21084"></span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#e07950">What are mystery boxes?</h2>
<p>Mystery boxes consist of a random assortment of goods from your online shop, which customers pay a fixed price for. Why would customers purchase a product when they don’t know what they’re getting? The pleasure of surprise is one reason, but the discount they’ll receive (up to 70% off!) is an even stronger motivating factor. But why, as a merchant, would you want to give such a large discount on your products? Because it’s the perfect opportunity to clear out remaining inventory, and make more room in your warehouse for next season’s products.</p>
<h2 style="color:#e07950">Which products work in a mystery box?</h2>
<p><u>Affordable Selection</u> &#8211; Customers who purchase mystery boxes are taking a chance. This means the product bundle must be priced well: customers should view it as a fun purchase that’s not overly expensive; the deal should be what grabs their attention. A good way to determine the price of your mystery box is to check the average<br />
order value (AOV) of customer purchases on your site. Try to keep your prices at or under that price point to make your offer more appealing. </p>
<p><u>General product</u> &#8211; Products that appeal to a general public are great for quickly putting together mystery boxes: one-size fits all, office supplies, toys and snacks are just a few products that fit this category. You could also consider offering more specific boxes segmented by your product attributes and categories if you have the time. For example, you could package clothes in mystery boxes by size. Take a look at your website structure to get ideas for your mystery box offering. Just stay clear of product customizations&#8211; they can be a mystery box buster. </p>
<p><u>Small-sized products</u> &#8211; Small items are an easy sell in mystery boxes. Your best bet would be to combine products that easily fit into a flat-rate box. Anything too large will be costly to ship and cut into your profit margin. Plus, customers will enjoy receiving a variety of goods, which can enhance the feeling of having gotten a deal.</p>
<h2 style="color:#e07950">Last minute tips</h2>
<p><u><strong>Create an FAQ.</strong></u> Address as many of your customer’s questions as possible, especially if it’s the first time you’re offering the deal. Common questions include: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Is shipping included? </li>
<li>Can items be exchanged? Returned? </li>
<li>What can customers generally expect?</li>
<li>What is the value of the package? </li>
<li>Is there a limit to the number of boxes a customer can purchase?</li>
</ul>
<p><u><strong>Offer great value.</strong></u> It may be tempting to provide customers with a random assortment of things they may or may not want. While that might be a great way to clear out your inventory, but you risk damaging your shop’s reputation if you don’t offer your customers the value you promise. Keep in mind that these customers are people who shop with you regularly, so they have a good sense of the value of each of your products. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e07950">It’s your turn</h2>
<ol>
<li>Determine how many mystery boxes you’d like to offer</li>
<li>List your product on your website</li>
<li>Promote your mystery box (via email, social media, or even your blog)</li>
<li>While you wait for orders to come in, brainstorm ways to encourage customers share their purchase.</li>
<li>Pack and ship your mystery boxes! </li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/clear-holiday-inventory-increase-sales-mystery-boxes/">Clear holiday inventory and increase sales with mystery boxes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/clear-holiday-inventory-increase-sales-mystery-boxes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grow your business abroad by catering to European customers’ payment habits</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/grow-business-abroad-catering-european-customers-payment-habits/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/grow-business-abroad-catering-european-customers-payment-habits/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 13:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21040</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Every country has its own unique purchasing habits. French people prefer shopping online, while consumers in the United Kingdom tends to lean towards m-commerce. Cyber-shoppers in some countries prefer home delivery, whereas others are fans of in-store pickup. These general habits also apply to payment solutions. E-merchants should therefore diversify the international payment solutions they [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/grow-business-abroad-catering-european-customers-payment-habits/">Grow your business abroad by catering to European customers’ payment habits</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every country has its own unique purchasing habits. French people prefer shopping online, while consumers in the United Kingdom tends to lean towards m-commerce. Cyber-shoppers in some countries prefer home delivery, whereas others are fans of in-store pickup. </p>
<p>These general habits also apply to payment solutions. E-merchants should therefore diversify the international payment solutions they make available to their customers.<br />
<span id="more-21040"></span><br />
<strong>Belgium and Germany: local payment solutions</strong><br />
In Belgium, bank cards account for only 40% of all online payments. Belgians prefer paying with national solutions such as Bancontact and Mister Cash and through online banks (ING Home’Pay, Belfius &amp; KBC CBC). These solutions hold a 52% market share for Belgian e-commerce sites.</p>
<p>Germans also prefer local payment methods: bank transfers – in particular through SOFORT – are used 4 times as much as bank cards: 25 million transactions were generated in 2014. </p>
<p><strong>Netherlands and Poland: bank transfers</strong><br />
iDEAL is the leading payment solution in the Netherlands with a 60% market share. All customers using online banking with a bank offering iDEAL are eligible for this simple and fast service. In Poland, bank transfers also feature prominently (28% market share), thanks to the Przelewy24 solution.</p>
<p><strong>Portugal and Italy: cash payments at retail outlets or through ATMs</strong><br />
These payment methods allow merchants to reach young populations without bank accounts in addition to audiences reluctant to disclose their bank account information online. These solutions are primarily used in countries such as Portugal and Italy where cash is the most popular form of payment. </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Multibanco is an ATM-based payment system that has generated 781 million transactions. 70% of Portuguese people pay their phone, gas and water bills with this payment method.</li>
<li>Lastly, with over 42,000 points of sale in Italy, SisalPay is the most popular payment method for online cosmetics purchases.</li>
</ul>
<p>The <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/1746-hipay.html?utm_source=prestashop.com&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_campaign=internal-linking&amp;utm_content=hipay" target="_blank">HiPay</a>, partner module, available for free in PrestaShop, lets you offer all of your customers&#8217; favorite local payment solutions with a single module and benefit from competitive prices, with no merchant services agreement.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/grow-business-abroad-catering-european-customers-payment-habits/">Grow your business abroad by catering to European customers’ payment habits</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/grow-business-abroad-catering-european-customers-payment-habits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Day in the Life of a Web Developer</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/day-life-web-developer/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/day-life-web-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21096</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The life of a web developer is glamorous. Every day involves mounting an inflatable raft to float around in a pool-sized jacuzzi filled with celebrities on the deck of a private portable island. From the comfort of my floating throne I write immaculate JavaScript functions using pure muscle memory. Alright, maybe you’ve figured out that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/day-life-web-developer/">A Day in the Life of a Web Developer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The life of a web developer is <em>glamorous</em>. Every day involves mounting an inflatable raft to float around in a pool-sized jacuzzi filled with celebrities on the deck of <a href="http://aplus.com/a/Kokomo-Ailand-Migaloo-private-submarines?c=2600" target="_blank">a private portable island</a>. From the comfort of my floating throne I write immaculate JavaScript functions using pure muscle memory.<br />
<span id="more-21096"></span><br />
Alright, maybe you’ve figured out that I’m not being entirely forthright with my introduction. I’m not sure what gave me away – the island thing? The life of a web developer resembles that of most professionals: eat, sleep, rest, enjoy your work, and occasionally watch as all hell breaks loose. Let’s start with the good.</p>
<h2 style="color: #0cb9cd">Don’t Bother Me</h2>
<p>I use the early hours of the day to complete my most important tasks. Things like bug fixes, new features, refactors, and more get done before everyone else makes it into the office. This is a quiet time when I am capable of reaching peak performance.</p>
<p>Without meetings, background noise, and visual distractions, I am capable of thinking clearly about my work. Some night-owls will conserve this level of energy until after 11 PM; then they slip on a pair of enormous headphones and lose track of when one trance rap ends and the other begins. Either way, developers get their best work done without distractions.</p>
<h2 style="color: #0cb9cd">Hey Look, the Internet!</h2>
<p>At many organizations, the hours between 11 AM and 3 PM are pretty calm. In between meetings and lunch, I usually take this time to read up on the industry. <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/" target="_blank">Hacker News</a>, <a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank">GitHub</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/" target="_blank">Stack Overflow</a>, and others provide a bevy of fun tidbits to dig into and share.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21098" alt="lifeofadev2" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/lifeofadev2.png" width="440" height="220" /></p>
<p>New APIs, frameworks, and tools seem to appear every day, and it’s part of every web developer’s job to keep their finger on the pulse of the industry. I play with these new tools, share them among my social network, and geek out about stuff like a new version of jQuery or an awesome animation library I can’t wait to integrate.</p>
<h2 style="color: #0cb9cd">I’m Working Again</h2>
<p>Sometime in the afternoon, I am ready to handle important work again. If I’m developing a popular web app, there’s likely a host of bugs in the backlog that need fixing.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21100" alt="lfieofadev3" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/lfieofadev3.jpg" width="500" height="354" /></p>
<p>Bugs come in all shapes and sizes, and occasionally they engage my interest. Not every bug is interesting, but nearly every bug deserves attention. I may spend anywhere from thirty minutes to several hours discovering the source of a bug. Depending on the nature of the issue, I might then spend anywhere from one minute to one week (or longer) fixing it. I pray for the one-minute versions.</p>
<h2 style="color: #0cb9cd">I Stumble into Hell</h2>
<p>The devil has been depicted in a variety of forms throughout history and across cultures, but most people know he’s really Al Pacino.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21099" alt="lifeofadev4" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/lifeofadev4.png" width="688" height="288" /></p>
<p>For web developers, the devil is a priority zero, product-breaking, user-facing bug that requires <em>immediate</em> fixing. About the time I’m getting ready to leave work, go home, and relax for the rest of the evening, the devil saunters into the office. Sometimes I’m not that lucky, and the devil visits on a Saturday morning at 3 AM instead.</p>
<p>He fills developer inboxes with app failure notifications and a stream of user complaints which we must read in full to milk them for valuable information. The devil keeps system administrators, web developers, project leads, and many more employees wide awake at unthinkable hours. Tracking the bug down, fixing it, deploying a rapid fix, then breaking all of that down into a post-mortem while running on two hours of sleep is likely the worst part of the job, and something many web devs experience.</p>
<h2 style="color: #0cb9cd">Personal Projects</h2>
<p>Every passionate developer takes their passion home at the end of the day. In my private time, I work on apps and tools to broaden my expertise and contribute to the community. Sometimes I will slave away at an app just for fun. I love to program and to build things that wouldn’t have existed otherwise.</p>
<p>I also love to solve problems for myself and will often dedicate hundreds of hours of my free time to doing so. Programming is fun, and if gone unchecked, can become addictive. But that’s why I also balance my activities with a healthy personal life filled with adventure…also in healthy doses.</p>
<h4 style="color: #0cb9cd">About Stan Idesis</h4>
<p>Stan Idesis worked as a Software Engineer at Zynga and Kwarter, and founded his own company, MindGap. He then joined Bloc, an online coding bootcamp that uses one-on-one mentorship to teach students how to <a href="https://www.bloc.io/software-engineering-track" target="_blank">become a software engineer</a> or web developer.</p>
<p>Already a software engineer? Check out PrestaShop’s <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/careers">career</a> page for current openings.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/day-life-web-developer/">A Day in the Life of a Web Developer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/day-life-web-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launch a subscription box in just 5 easy steps</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/launch-subscription-box-just-5-easy-steps/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/launch-subscription-box-just-5-easy-steps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 13:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21032</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In late 2012, online shoppers fell under the spell of subscription boxes. Today, their interest is at an all-time high, so we’d like to give you a few pointers on how to start your own subscription box program. Whether you’re just starting out in ecommerce, or you’re already running a successful store, launching this type [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/launch-subscription-box-just-5-easy-steps/">Launch a subscription box in just 5 easy steps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In late 2012, online shoppers fell under the spell of <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/66034-the-pros-and-cons-of-subscription-ecommerce-models/" target="_blank">subscription boxes</a>. Today, their interest is at an all-time high, so we’d like to give you a few pointers on how to start your own subscription box program. Whether you’re just starting out in ecommerce, or you’re already running a successful store, launching this type of program can be a great way to build predictable revenue and grow your long-term customer base.<br />
<span id="more-21032"></span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/12/subscriptio-boxes.png" alt="subscriptio-boxes" width="864" height="463" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21033" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">Why should you consider launching a subscription box?</h2>
<p>The idea behind <a href="https://blog.kissmetrics.com/subcom/" target="_blank">subscription commerce</a> is that your customers pay a monthly fee to receive a selection of goods from your store. From <a href="http://www.fashionstork.com/" target="_blank">fashion</a> to food, any product you can offer on a recurring basis has a potential spot in a box. To start brainstorming your own offer, check out <a href="http://www.mysubscriptionaddiction.com/" target="_blank">MySubscriptionAddiction.com</a>. </p>
<p>Subscription boxes have multiple advantages. First, the recurring nature of subscriptions allows you to <strong>predict demand and volume every month</strong>, which reduces uncertainty and waste. It also gives you a relatively stable, predictable revenue without the wild peaks that traditional retail stores experience. </p>
<p>Secondly, the subscription model reduces a certain number of costs. The predictable nature of this business model makes stock, shipping costs, and resource needs easier to estimate ahead of time. It also requires less investment in retention spend; instead of constantly chasing after new customers for sales, you’ll focus a bit more on keeping loyal customers happy.</p>
<p>Finally, the subscription model is based on a long-term relationship with customers, as opposed to a one-off sale. The advantage is that you’ve got an open line of communication with your customers and regular opportunities to check in and get feedback&#8211;which you’ll absolutely need to do to keep your offer fresh and convincing. If you succeed, your brand will become an integral part of your customers’ lives, offering convenience and delight they can’t find anywhere else. Here’s how you get started.</p>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">1) Decide what you’re going to sell</h2>
<p>Once you’ve decided to go for a subscription box, the first question you need to answer is obviously “What am I going to sell?” If you already have an ecommerce store, you might use a subscription box to test out products on your customers, a little like Birchbox. Customers who discover your products through “samples” or single servings may be more willing to buy full-size versions from your main store.</p>
<p>If you plan to make a subscription box the focus of your business model like <a href="http://www.kiwicrate.com/" target="_blank">Kiwi Crate</a>, you’ll have to approach it like you would any other online business: you need to be knowledgeable or at least passionate about the sector; there needs to be a market for your product; and you need the time to dedicate to building the business. For help tackling this initial planning stage, download our free guide to drawing up a <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-business-plan">business plan</a>. </p>
<p>The regularity and predictability of subscription boxes can also be their downside. Make sure you keep your offer fresh and exciting. Use the connection you have with your customers to hone in on what they want to receive and tailor your boxes to be unique. Try to offer products that customers won’t find anywhere else. Otherwise you risk seeing them unsubscribe&#8211;and there goes your regular cash flow.</p>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">2) Get operational</h2>
<p>If you already have a store, you’ll recognize most of the questions about the back end of running a subscription box; it’s similar to running a traditional ecommerce business. However, the fact that you’re packing multiple items every month requires you to be a bit more organized. Inventory levels and the packing process are going to be key touch points. Here are a few questions to consider: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Will you be buying the products that go in the box, or will you only provide manufacturer samples?</li>
<li>Where will inventory be stored?</li>
<li>How will you select your products?</li>
<li>Where will you source products </li>
<li>Who will pack the boxes?</li>
<li>Are your supplier(s) reliable? How many do you need?</li>
<li>How will you <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners">track and ship your packages</a>?</li>
<li>How much does the inventory cost?</li>
<li>How much profit do you plan to make per box?</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">3) Market your offer</h2>
<p>Once you’ve done all your research and decided on the customer segment you’ll target, it’s time to promote your subscription box. Social media platforms like <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-leverage-pinterest-for-your-online-store/">Pinterest</a> and Instagram are great places to start. Get <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/">key influencers</a> to promote your brand or co-market your box with you. This works well for subscription boxes that draw on a variety of well-known brands or focus on a lifestyle segment, like makeup or speciality food products.</p>
<p>Subscription boxes offer a unique opportunity to build community, since they typically respond to a recurring and essential need in your customer’s life. Long-term customer acquisition is at the core of your business, so it will pay off to focus on creating value that your subscribers will be excited to share with others. </p>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">4) Launch your website</h2>
<p>As you launch your campaigns, you’ll want to start configuring your <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/">online shop</a> to accept orders. Whether they are pre-sale or active orders, your ecommerce platform should easily keep track of all vital information. As you scale up, here are a few features you’ll want to have:</p>
<div style="padding-left:30px">
	<u>Recurring billing</u> &#8211; Ensure your <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/481-payment" target="_blank">payment solution</a> offers secure options for storing customer credit card information and automating the monthly billing process.</p>
<p>	<u>Integrated Shipping</u> &#8211; Look for a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/518-shipping-logistics" target="_blank">shipping solution</a> that is integrated with your software. You’ll save time generating labels and expedite the shipping process. As an added bonus, find a solution that automatically updates the order with each package’s shipping information. Also look for a solution that has pre-negotiated bulk rates to keep your initial costs low. </p>
<p>	<u>Automated <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/8300-sendinblue.html" target="_blank">Emailing</a></u> &#8211; Once you’ve billed customers and shipped the subscription box, it’s time to let your customers know when they can expect their package. For a more personal touch, personalize each email to the contents of that month’s box.
</div>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">5) Listen to your customers</h2>
<p>You’ve launched your subcom business&#8211;now the real work can begin. To keep customers happy, create a continuous feedback loop and use what you learn to improve your offer. You might set up a monthly survey to get an idea of what customers enjoyed receiving, what they didn’t appreciate, and what they’d like to see more of. Remember, your customers could just as easily go to the store and pick up whatever you put in your subscription box: your added value is in how you curate your offer. You provide simplicity and convenience that a regular store can’t.</p>
<p>Your biggest challenge will be proving the value of a recurring subscription. You’ll be working against the monthly question your customers ask themselves: is this monthly payment still worth it? </p>
<p>Personalization, careful curation and constant communication will help make sure they keep saying “yes.”</p>
<h2 style="color:#43367e">Real-world Example</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/12/real-world.png" alt="real-world" width="883" height="456" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21034" /></p>
<p>For more inspiration, check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/download/pdf/02-fashion-stork.pdf" target="_blank">case study</a> on the PrestaShop store, Fashion Stork. After the business he worked for folded, owner Emmanuel Fey, used his experience, industry connections and life savings to launch Fashion Stork, a fashion subscription box for men. Visit their website to see a successful example of a subscription box business. </p>
<hr align="left" width="20%">
<p>Ready to kick off 2016? Start your own online business today. Already running a subcom business? Share tips that’ve kept you in business in the comments. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/launch-subscription-box-just-5-easy-steps/">Launch a subscription box in just 5 easy steps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/launch-subscription-box-just-5-easy-steps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 New Year&#8217;s Resolutions for 2016 from the PrestaTeam</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-new-years-resolutions-2016-prestateam/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-new-years-resolutions-2016-prestateam/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 17:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21008</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s a new year, which means it’s time to start new habits that will make you a better&#8230;well, you. We asked around the office to see what resolutions the PrestaTeam is making. Here are 6 that every merchant can adopt. We promise, they’re easier to keep than that fancy new diet you read about on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-new-years-resolutions-2016-prestateam/">6 New Year&#8217;s Resolutions for 2016 from the PrestaTeam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s a new year, which means it’s time to start new habits that will make you a better&#8230;well, you. We asked around the office to see what resolutions the PrestaTeam is making. Here are 6 that every merchant can adopt. We promise, they’re easier to keep than that fancy new diet you read about on Buzzfeed.<br />
<span id="more-21008"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a">1) Make new friends.</h2>
<p>It seems that as we get older, we make less time for making new friends. So in 2016, we vow to turn off our computers, put down our phones and get out and meet new people! We’re going to join MeetUp.com, attend PrestaShop community events, and say “yes” to the next invitation we receive. It’s a great way to practice our social skills and maybe even make some new friends. Who knows? If you try it too, you might just meet your next business partner!<br />
<strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/preston/" target="_blank">Preston &#8211; PrestaShop Mascot</a></strong></p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a">2) Take a vacation.</h2>
<p>Entrepreneurs, let’s just admit it: we’re workaholics. Our drive to solve everyday problems makes us successful at our business. But this year, we’re going to put the problem solving on hold for a bit. We’re hitting the road. Whether it’s taking short cruise or driving the length of Route 66, we’re determined to see another part of the world. Although it may feel like time taken away from our business, we’re going to use it as time to refuel and maybe even come up with some new ideas for the company.<br />
<strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/author/julieliu/">Julie Liu</a> &#8211; Marketing Specialist </strong></p>
<p>Need inspiration? Check out all the <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/prestashop/meet-preston/" target="_blank">cities our mascot</a>, Preston has visited in 2015!</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a">3) Adopt a pet.</h2>
<p>Having a dog may seem counterintuitive: do you really need more responsibility? But having someone else depend on you also gives you motivation to get your life in order: get up early every morning (forget about sleeping until noon), eat at reasonable meal times, get home at a decent hour&#8230;establishing a regular rhythm will help you keep your store on track as well. And best of all, you&#8217;ll get plenty of love all day long, which will decrease stress levels and boost your morale when you&#8217;re filling out all your product data sheets!<br />
<strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/forums/user/1117607-sylvain-dermy/" target="_blank">Sylvain Dermy</a> &#8211; Community Manager</strong></p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a">4) <a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size: 28px;font-weight: 300" href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/training-prestashop">Learn something new!</a></h2>
<p>There’s a saying that you can’t teach an old dog new tricks. Well, thank goodness you’re not a dog. <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" />  With such a wide variety of online resources available, it’s easier than ever to learn something new. We suggest <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-ways-to-learn-how-to-code-like-an-ecommerce-developer/">learning how to code</a>. Not only will you start to understand what your developer is saying, but you might be able to squash some bugs on your website yourself!<br />
<strong>Danny Moreno &#8211; Technical Support</strong></p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a">5) Be more Social &#8211; online that is.</h2>
<p>Have you abandoned your social media followers in the midst of the holiday rush? This year, we’re committed to speaking and listening to our fans! Although we can’t say “‘yes” to everything, we’re going to say it as much as we can. It’s important that we build a good relationship with our fans, and not just continuously promote our products. We’re passionate about what we sell, and that’s what we want to share with our fans.<br />
<strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/author/kate/">Kate Robinson</a> &#8211; Content Manager</strong></p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a">6) Make no resolutions.</h2>
<p>Let’s be realistic for once: no one keeps their resolutions. Why not sell exercise equipment in the first week of January, and then snack foods for the rest of the year. Now that’s what we call understanding your customers. <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /><br />
<strong>Brenna Verner &#8211; Merchant Success Specialist &#8211; <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Addons</a> </strong></p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>How do you plan on improving in 2016? Let us know in the comments below! and most importantly…</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a"><strong>Happy 2016 from the PrestaShop family! </strong></h2>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-new-years-resolutions-2016-prestateam/">6 New Year&#8217;s Resolutions for 2016 from the PrestaTeam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-new-years-resolutions-2016-prestateam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
